-*- 心灵教育 -*-
When we use the word soul
当我们谈论 “灵魂” 这个词时，
we're reaching for
我们是在寻找
one of the few available words to name
为数不多的可以用来命名
that which has no name.
那无以名状之物的几个词之一。
We're reaching for the inner mystery of
我们正在探索 “灵魂” 对于
what it means to be human.
人类内在奥秘的意义。
I sometimes call it the Three In The Morning Experience.
我有时称它为 “凌晨三点体验”。
When you wake up and realize
当你醒来时发现，
I'm not my role
我不是我所扮演的角色，
I'm not my latest failure or success,
我不是眼前的失败或成功，
I am just, what, me, I am a self,
我是灵性的自我。
In some religious traditions,
在一些宗教传统中会有这样的描述：
I am a child of God
我是上帝的孩子；
I am a created being.
我是上天所造的灵性的存有。
And that's all I need by way of justification.
这就是我所能给出的所有理由。
There's an inner voice I think
我感到有一个内在的
that wants to keep telling me that
声音一直试图告诉我，
a voice that wants to keep saying:
一个一直在述说的声音：
"Don't get hung up on
"不要纠结于
either your failures or your successes."
个人的失败或成功"。
You have only one gift to give in this world
你唯一可以给予这个世界的礼物，
and that's, who you are,
那就是，你是谁，
your identity and integrity, your selfhood.
你的自身认同和身心完整。
And stay as close to that gift as you possibly can.
尽己所能地靠近那个礼物。
Most of us understand that along the line
我们大多数人都明白根据这个指引，
we're going to find particular forms of giving that gift.
我们将找到给予这个礼物的特定形式。
We're going to become engineers
我们将成为工程师，
or we're going to become parents
或成为父母，
or we're going to be try to be good citizens
或努力做个好公民，
or we're going to be doctors
或成为医生，
or hairdressers or clerks who are helpful.
或成为乐于助人的理发师或职员。
And that there are some skills
每个角色都有
associated with each of those roles
一些相关的技能
and that there's knowledge associated with
并且有与做好每个角色
doing each of those roles well.
相关的知识。
So I'm not blinking the fact
所以我不否认
that there's work to be done
要在世界上做好服务
to serve well in the world.
还有很多事要做。
But ultimately
但最终来说，
the only service I have to render
我唯一能提供的服务，
the only gift I have to give is myself.
我唯一能给出的礼物就是我自己。
That mystery that I sometimes call soul
那个神秘的东西，我有时称之为灵魂，
and sometimes call spirit and
有时称之为灵性，
sometimes call identity and integrity.
有时候称之为身份认同和身心完整。
But it's that inwardness from which everything else comes.
它是一种内在的东西，其它的东西都来自于此。
We know it's so interesting to me that
对我而言很有趣的是，
we want to ignore this inwardness
我们想忽视这种内在的东西，
we want to ignore I'll call it the education of the heart.
我们试图忽略我称之为心灵的教育。
Always because we're so obsessed with educating
因为我们如此执迷于
people to make the right moves.
教育人们做出正确的动作。
Every form of professional education I've ever seen is
我所见过的每种形式的专业教育
about making the right moves
几乎都是关于规范正确的动作
to qualify you as a member of this profession.
以让你有资格成为这个行业的一员。
The truth is there's a secret hidden in plain sight.
事实是，有一个秘密隐藏在显而易见的地方。
We know that you can move a knife with enormous skill
我们知道你可以有高超的用刀技巧
in order to murder somebody;
来夺人性命；
we also know that you can
我们也知道你可以
move a knife with enormous skill
用高超的用刀技巧
in order to heal somebody.
来疗愈他人。
What makes the difference between those two acts
这两种行动之间的区别
is not the skillfulness of the hand that holds the knife
不在于握刀之手的技巧，
it's the heart that moves the hand.
而是动手的那颗心。
And if we don't start getting as concerned about
如果我们不着手关注
educating that heart that spirit that soul
教育的那颗心、那个灵性、那个灵魂，
whatever you want to call it.
不管你怎么称呼它是什么。
That human inwardness from which
在人类内在深处
work of every sort flows.
有各种各样的活动在其中流动着。
If we continue to be obsessed with
如果我们继续沉迷于
the skillfulness that with which the hand moves
奇技淫巧，
we're just missing the point.
我们就没抓住重点。
And we're not educating people
而且我们没有教育人们
for the healing work that the world needs.
服务于这个世界所需要的疗愈工作。